A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 17727-19980 FA739G
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom reflection memos: Worldwide Meeting: November 13 -20, 2005, Johannesburg, South Africa (Reports 018499) (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memos on Knowledge, Creativity & Freedom program for 2005.[…]KC&F staff: A. Bernstein, David Chiel, Janice Petrovich, Jorge Balan, Constance H. Buchanan, Cyrus Driver, Ondina Fachel Leal, Chris Martin, Barbara Klugman, Maria Amelia Palacios, Galina Rakhmanova, Carla Sutherland, Margaret B. Wilkerson, Orlando Blackw
  Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom
  Human rights -- South Africa -- Congresses; Congresses and conventions -- South Africa; Apartheid -- Africa -- Congresses
- Reflection memo (Reports 018500), 2000 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Religious institutions -- Social aspects -- United States; Community development -- Religion; At-risk youth -- Rehabilitation -- United States -- Religion; African American youth -- Religious life
- Reflection memo (Reports 018501), 2007 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Workforce -- United States; Economic conditions -- United States; Poor -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018502), 2002 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Education -- Vietnam
- Reflection memo (Reports 018503), 2003 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018504), 2006 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018505), 2007 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018506), 2006 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This reflection memo covers the Human Rights Program activities in Fiscal Year 2006 (from October 2005 to September 2006).[…]Memo to Ana Toni, dated September 20, 2006.
  Peace and Social Justice/Human Rights and International Cooperation
  Human rights -- Brazil; Race discrimination -- Brazil; Sex discrimination -- Brazil; Endowments -- Brazil -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo (Reports 018507), 2002 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by Cyrus Driver evaluating the challenges raised concerning K-12 and community college reform, seen in connection with racial and social inequalities.
  Education, Higher -- United States; Racial discrimination -- Social aspects -- United States; People with social disadvantages -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018508), 2003 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018509), 2004 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This portfolio has evolved greatly the past six years to reflect my views on effective strategies to institutionalize large-scale improvements in the quality of urban public schools and community college systems. Strategies have focused on three dimension
- Reflection memo (Reports 018510), 2006 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018511), 2007 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Governance and Civil Society/Peace and Social Justice
  Political participation -- Iraq; Civil society -- Iraq; Political participation -- China; Civil society -- China
- Reflection memo (Reports 018512), 2002 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by Cristina Eguizabal concerning the status of the Latin American political landscape, with emphasis placed on U.S. relations with Southern Cone areas, Mexico and Cuba.
  Latin America and the Caribbean/Mexico and Central America
  Public opinion -- Latin America; Elections
- Reflection memo: Assets program retreat memo (Reports 018513), 2005 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  Assets program all-day retreat on October 6, 2005 to discuss reflection memos
  Economic development; Social change; Community development -- Finance
- Reflection memo (Reports 018514), 2005 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This memo reflects on the work of the Human Rights portfolio in West Africa in FY 2005.
  Social justice -- Africa, West; Human rights -- Africa, West; Endowments -- Africa, West -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo (Reports 018515), 2006 (Box 888, Reel R-9324)
  This memo reflects on the work of the Human Rights portfolio in West Africa in FY 2006. As anticipated in last year's reflection memo, the POM was finally approved in March 2006, allowing me to work with initiatives and re-organize my grants going forward
- Reflection memo (Reports 018516), 2004 (Box 889, Reel R-9324)
  Reflection memo prepared by Roshmi Goswami evaluating trends in and political implications on the sexuality and reproductive health portfolio.
  Health services for women -- India; Reproductive health -- India; Women -- India -- Social aspects; Women's rights -- India; Marginalization -- India; Gender role
- Reflection memo (Reports 018517), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9324)
  The East European Program is in a transitional moment. This is the Program's last budget year and all of its activities are focused on securing its achievements. We are tying off all the grantees, paying attention to those among them on whom a larger last
  Civil society -- Europe, Eastern; Human rights -- Europe, Eastern; Public interest law
- Reflection memo (Reports 018518), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9324)
  Social justice -- Endowments
- Reflection memo (Reports 018519), 2001 (Box 889, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018520), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9324)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018521), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  The portfolio on philanthropy is constructed to support two initiatives. The first is a set of work to strengthen the philanthropic infrastructure with a strong emphasis on foundation accountability. The second and larger initiative encourages work to exp
- Reflection memo (Reports 018522), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  The Ford Foundation has over many decades supported philanthropy and its infrastructure because it sees philanthropy as a critical, but generic public good. In the Foundation's view, organized philanthropy provides important resources to civil society org
- Reflection memo (Reports 018523), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  This reflection memo tries to capture some of my observations and the critical lessons the author has learned since beginning work in Southern Africa in September of 2001.
  Decentralization in government -- Citizen participation -- Africa, Southern; Community development -- Citizen participation -- Africa, Southern
- Reflection memo (Reports 018524), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  This reflection memo will address lessons learned and share a number of observations that have emerged since the completion of the last memo at the end of calendar year 2002. It is being written at a time when the first draft of my Program Officer Memo fo
- Reflection memo (Reports 018525), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Human rights advocacy -- Minorities -- United States; Human rights advocacy -- Refugees -- United States; Migrant labor -- United States; Human rights advocacy -- Refugees -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018526), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  On June 28, 2007, a comprehensive immigration reform bill developed by a bipartisan group of Senators and the White House was derailed when it failed to secure the 60 votes needed to end debate and to bring the bill for a vote before the entire Senate. De
- Reflection memo (Reports 018527), 2005 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  "This memorandum is written six months into my start date at the Ford Foundation. As such, I have not yet written my POM. What follows are therefore my thoughts as to where the fields of U.S. foreign and security policy currently stand, where these fields
  National security -- United States; Security, International; International relations; World politics; Human rights; War on Terrorism, 2001-2009; Iraq War, 2003-
- Reflection memo (Reports 018528), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Education -- China; Vocational training -- China; Educational change -- China; Student aspirations -- China; Education and state -- China
- Reflection memo (Reports 018529), 2004 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  As the country context has not changed much since the approval of my POM in early 2004, thismemo will focus on my programme work in 2003-2004. Then I will use one case study to reflecton the strategy of my grant-making in the past three years.
- Reflection memo (Reports 018530), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo: Strengthening global civil society (Reports 018531), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Lisa Jordan evaluating changes in the civil society field in areas of policy and human rights.
  Civil society; International relations; Globalization; World politics; Non-governmental organizations
- Reflection memo: Strengthening global civil society (Reports 018532), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018533), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  The main change since the 2006 reflection memo has been the dramatic rise in concern about global warming. The combination of Al Gore's movie, the Stern report, Hurricane Katrina, melting glaciers, Schwarzenegger's climate initiative, the Inter-government
  Sustainable forestry; Ecotourism; Poor; Forests and forestry -- Economic aspects; Natural resource conservation; Women's rights
- Reflection memo (Reports 018534), 2001 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Civil society -- International cooperation; Citizenship -- Egypt; Citizenship -- Palestine
- Reflection memo (Reports 018535), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  The field of Governance and Civil Society in the Arab world is one that fluctuates between periods of promising prospects of liberalization and periods of regression. It is clear that the current period is of the latter type. NGOs, research centers and do
- Reflection memo (Reports 018536), 2001 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Community development -- Egypt; Community development -- Palestine; Community development -- Middle East; Community development -- North Africa; Youth; Community leadership
- Reflection memo (Reports 018537), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018538), 2004 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Human Development and Reproductive Health
  Reproductive health -- Research -- Brazil; Medical care -- Research -- Brazil; Health services accessibility -- Brazil; Hygiene, Sexual -- Brazil; Medical policy -- Brazil; Social sciences -- Research -- Brazil
- Reflection memo: period September 2005 (Reports 018539), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Microfinance -- Andes Region; Small business -- Finance -- Andes Region; Economic development -- Andes Region; Endowments -- Andes Region -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo (Reports 018540), 2004 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Environment and Development Program
  Environmental protection -- China; Economic development -- Environmental aspects -- China; Non-governmental organizations -- China; Natural resources -- Management -- China
- Reflection memo (Reports 018541), 2001 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Government -- United States -- Public opinion; Government -- Programs -- United States -- Awards; Expenditures, Public -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018542), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  By previous agreement this memo reports on the status of the State Fiscal Analysis Initiative. SFAI is the most substantial component of my work these days. A full treatment of SFAI should allow us to explore in a timely way any issues that might be raise
- Reflection memo (Reports 018543), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Resource-based communities -- China; Forestry and community -- China; Natural resources -- China -- Management
- Reflection memo (Reports 018544), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Chris Martin analyzing the education program initiatives in Mexico and Central America, with emphasis placed on promoting educational opportunity to a wider population, specifically indigenous populations.
  Extent
  5 p.
  Education, Higher -- Latin America; Civil rights -- Latin America; Marginalization -- Latin America; Indigenous peoples -- Education
- Reflection memo (Reports 018545), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by George McCarthy on status of financial planning for low-income persons portfolio, with emphasis on housing, asset preservation and market development.
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Education
  Home ownership; Foreclosure -- Law and legislation; Manufactured houses; Energy assistance to the poor; Housing rehabilitation; Economically disadvantaged; Financial planning industry; Community development; Money lenders
- Reflection memo (Reports 018546), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Irma McClaurin evaluating the education and scholarhip portfolio, focusing on work in diversification for both African American education and women - gender studies.
  African Americans -- Education, Higher -- United States; Women's studies -- United States; Women's rights -- United States; Feminism and education
- Reflection memo (Reports 018547), 2000 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reproductive health -- Thailand; Reproductive health -- Vietnam; Violence against women -- Thailand; HIV-positive persons -- Violence against -- Thailand; Social sciences -- Research
- Reflection memo (Reports 018548), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Bishnu Mohapatra evaluating governance and democracy in South Asia, with emphasis on India, Sri Lanka and Nepal.
  Democracy -- India; Public administration -- India; Nationalism -- India; Public policy -- India
- Reflection memo (Reports 018549), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Economic policy; Developing countries; Economic development; Policy -- Development -- Women
- Reflection memo (Reports 018550), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018551), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Women's rights -- Africa, Southern; Human rights -- Africa, Southern; Social justice -- Africa, Southern; Endowments -- Africa, Southern -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo office for West Africa (Reports 018552), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Microfinance -- Nigeria; Economic development -- Nigeria; Environmental policy -- Africa, West
- Reflection memo (Reports 018553), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Development finance institutions in Mexico and Central America are poised for significant expansion over the next five years provided that the ongoing development of a supportive mixture of innovative methods and policies continues. The extension of quali
  Microfinance -- Latin America; Microenterprise lending -- Latin America; Microcredit -- Latin America; Financial services industry -- Latin America; Economic security -- Latin America; Rural credit -- Latin America
- Reflection memo (Reports 018554), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018555), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by William Okedi analyzing the Johannesburg office portfolio related to HIV/AIDS grantmaking.
  South Africa; Safe sex in AIDS prevention; Stigma (Social psychology); Public health -- Research -- South Africa; AIDS (Disease) -- Epidemiology; AIDS (Disease) -- Moral and ethical aspects -- South Africa; HIV (Viruses) -- South Africa
- Reflection memo (Reports 018556), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Savings accounts -- Children -- United States; Credit unions -- United States; Financial services industry -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018557), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018558), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Maria Palacios discussing education and teaching practices in Argentina, Chile, Peru and Colombia.
  Latin America and the Caribbean/Argentia and the Southern Cone
  Educational change -- Andes Region; Education equalization -- Andes Region; Educational change -- Chile; Discrimination in education -- Andes Region
- Reflection memo (Reports 018559), 2005 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018560), 2001 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018561), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Human rights advocacy -- Russia (Federation); Social justice -- Russia (Federation); Human rights -- Russia (Federation)
- Reflection memo: education, sexuality and religion (Reports 018562), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Education, Media, Arts, and Culture program -- Education, Knowledge, & Religion [Education, Media, Arts, and Culture program (Education, Media, Arts and Culture)/EKR]; Education, Media, Arts, and Culture program (Education, Media, Arts and Culture)/EKR
  Education, Higher -- Endowments; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Universities and colleges -- Endowments
- Reflection memo (Reports 018563), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Betsy Theobald Richards outlining the portfolio's interest in Native American arts and culture.
  Indian art -- North America; Indians of North America -- Material culture; Indigenous art -- North America; Indigenous peoples -- Politics and government; Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights -- North America
- Reflection memo (Reports 018564), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018565), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Racial discrimination; Minorities--Civil rights; Equality; Social justice
- Reflection memo (Reports 018566), 2001 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Panchayat -- India -- Rural conditions; Public interest -- India; Pluralism (Social sciences)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018567), 2005 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Asia/India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Forest conservation -- India; Forest management -- India; Environmental protection -- India; Environmental policy -- India; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo (Reports 018568), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018569), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Economic security -- Vietnam; Economic development -- Vietnam; Rural development -- Vietnam; Land tenure -- Vietnam; Endowments -- Vietnam -- Evaluation
- Reflection memo (Reports 018570), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Alta Starr outlining the portfolio's interest in civil society, with emphasis placed on citizen participation in governance, public sphere access, and social justice organizations.
  Civil society -- United States; Civil rights -- United States; Democracy -- United States; Citizen's associations -- United States; Social justice -- United States; Bureaucracy -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018571), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Civil society -- United States; Social justice -- United States; Discrimination -- United States; Social movements -- United States; Student movements -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018572), 2003 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018573), 2005 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Thomasina H. Williams evaluating the portfolio's interest in democracy and politics in America, with emphasis on diversity, leadership, and voting rights and participation.
  Civic leaders -- United States; Political participation -- United States; Politics, Practical -- United States; Voter registration -- United States; Voting rights -- United States; Democracy -- United States
- Reflection memo (Reports 018574), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Susan Wood of the Vietnam and Thailand office, addressing human rights, sexuality and reproductive health issues, specifically HIV/AIDS awareness and growing gender-based violence concerns in Vietnam.
  Reproductive health -- Vietnam; Reproductive health -- Thailand; HIV/AIDS Infections -- Thailand; HIV/AIDS Infection -- Vietnam; Human sexuality -- Research; Sexually transmitted diseases; Violence; Sex role; Human rights; Youth and development
- Reflection memo (Reports 018575), 2004 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Irina Yurna of the Moscow office analyzing the portfolio's interest in arts and culture.
  Contemporary art -- Russia (Federation); Humanities -- Russia (Federation); Arts -- Russia (Federation); Motion pictures -- Russia (Federation); Archives -- Collection management
- Reflection memo (Reports 018576), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018577), 2007 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Education, Higher -- Russia (Federation)
- Reflection memo (Reports 018578), 2002 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Reflection memo prepared by Vernice Miller-Travis evaluating state of environmental justice. The movement has grown in some important facets, but it also seems to be sliding backwards in some key areas. One of the grants we made last year (to Vallecitos M
  Social change; Economic development -- United States; Natural resources -- Economic aspects -- United States; Natural resources -- Conservation -- United States
- International intellectual property initiative -- reflection memo (Reports 018579), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Intellectual property; Patent laws and legislation; Copyright -- Social aspects; Information society; Digitized records
- Reflection memo (Reports 018580), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  This memo provides an important opportunity to reflect on the broad political, social and economic context of Brazil and how has that effect overall the work of the Rio Office. As each PO has written their own reflection memo with the specificity of their
  Politics and government -- Brazil; Human rights -- Brazil
- Media initiative - Rio office - media pool - reflection memo (Reports 018581), 2005 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  The goal of this office-wide initiative is to revitalize and qualify the debate around media public Brazil, with the objective to foster a more democratic, diverse and plural media in Brazil.
  Media, Arts, and Culture
  Mass media -- Brazil
- DRAFT - Reflection memo Portfolio GSC - Rio office (Reports 018582), 2006 (Box 889, Reel R-9325)
  Politics and government -- Brazil; Philanthropy -- Brazil
- Education and promotion among the staff of the Delhi University Library (mimeo) (Reports 018583) (ED 68-9a), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-9a)
- Staff development: training for human relations and organizational effectiveness (mimeo) (Reports 018584) (ED 68-9b), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-9b)
- Library consulting in India for the Ford Foundation (mimeo) (Reports 018585) (ED 68-10), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-10)
- A prediction of the future: the development program of the University of Delhi Library (mimeo) (Reports 018586) (ED 68-11a), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-11a)
- Memorandum (mimeo) (Reports 018587) (ED 68-11b), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-11b)
  Sent to B. N. Ganguli.
- End of tour report (mimeo) (Reports 018588) (ED 68-13), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-13)
- End of tour report - University of Calcutta project business and finance (mimeo) (Reports 018589) (ED 68-14), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-14)
  Sent to Douglas Ensminger
- The responsibility of a teacher (mimeo) (Reports 018590) (ED 68-16), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-16)
- Memorandum end of tour report - Dr. Malcolm M. Willey (mimeo) (Reports 018591) (ED 68-17), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-17)
  Sent to all professional staff
- Survey of some Indian law schools and their development potential (mimeo) (Reports 018592) (ED 68-18c), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-18c)
- The role of faculty in institutional planning (mimeo) (Reports 018593) (ED 68-21), 1968 (Box 936, Sheet ED 68-21)
- Justicemakers: making racial justice newsworthy: a report to the Ford Foundation's Human Rights and International Cooperation and Media, Arts and Culture Programs (Reports 018594), 2000 (Box 890, Reel R-9325)
  In a cross-cutting initiative of its Human Rights and International Cooperation and Media, Arts and Culture programs, the Ford Foundation plans to fund a new joint program aimed at raising public awareness of racial discrimination in the United States and
  Human Rights and International Cooperation; Media, Arts, and Culture
  Related Grant Number
  10001232
  Discrimination -- United States; Human rights -- United States; Minorities in mass media -- United States
- Blooms of knowledge: learning from initiatives addressing violence against women (Reports 018595), 2003 (Box 890, Reel R-9325)